<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rancher on Neon Mirrors</title>
    <link>https://neonmirrors.net/tags/rancher/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rancher on Neon Mirrors</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2020, Chip Zoller and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://neonmirrors.net/tags/rancher/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>pks-rancher-reg: Automated PKS Cluster Registration For Rancher</title>
      <link>https://neonmirrors.net/post/2019-10/pks-rancher-reg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neonmirrors.net/post/2019-10/pks-rancher-reg/</guid>
      <description>My previous blog showed a method that can be used to stand up Rancher Server in HA on VMware PKS, and I’m going to build on it in this one. Having a Rancher Server environment is great for managing all sorts of Kubernetes clusters from the edge to those hosted in cloud providers, but we can also use it to manage VMware PKS clusters as well. That’s really no secret. However, since PKS focuses on a high degree of difficult automation to produce ready-to-run Kubernetes clusters at the end of the day, wouldn’t it be nice to extend that to making them ready-to-manage as well?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rancher HA on Enterprise PKS</title>
      <link>https://neonmirrors.net/post/2019-09/rancher-ha-on-pks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neonmirrors.net/post/2019-09/rancher-ha-on-pks/</guid>
      <description>Rancher is a container orchestration and management tool that has been around for several years at this point and performs a variety of different functions. In more recent days, it has been refactored to completely adopt Kubernetes. In this blog, I am going to focus on how to build an enterprise-grade, highly-available, and secure installation of Rancher Server on top of VMware Enterprise PKS. I’ll respond to the burning question of ‘why Rancher on PKS in the first place?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>